<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tracks]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.getontracks.org/tracks/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.getontracks.org/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-04T15:04:54+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.getontracks.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[TracksApp]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[tracks@getontracks.org]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Release Candidate 1 of Tracks 2.1 released]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.getontracks.org/news/comments/release-2.1.rc1/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-04T14:45:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.getontracks.org/news/comments/release-2.1.rc1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hi all,</p>

<p>It is finally release candidate time! You can now <a href="https://github.com/TracksApp/tracks/zipball/v2.1RC1">download</a> Tracks version 2.1 RC1 from github. Please try it out to see if you think it is ready for public release. Any problems you have can be posted to <a href="www.assembla.com/spaces/tracks-tickets/">Assembla</a>. Improvements for translations are welcome too.</p>

<p>I will update the installation and upgrade manual soon. I am talking to BSAG to find out how to do this on getontracks.org after the migration of the site to github. In general, you can follow the upgrade manual. Do not forget to migrate your database if you are coming from 2.0. And since we have migrated to bundler for managing dependencies, run &#8220;bundle install&#8221; (instead of rake gems:install). If you use passenger and the gems will not load using bundler, set the BUNDLER_PATH in .bundler/config.</p>

<p>We have seen a lot of new contributions from several contributers: Ignacio Ihuerta, Christof Spies, Stefan Richter, Mickey Reiss, Demian Gemperli, Matt Rogers, Jan Stępień, Antonin Blanc, Christian Frank, Sebastian Fischmeister, Andreas Brandl, Craig Maloney, Pavel Zupa, Tim Madden, Jaime Hernandez</p>

<p>Also we have two new committing developers (Hi Matt Rogers and Stefan Richter) to keep development of Tracks going. Thanks to all of you!!</p>

<p>For developers: to get to the stable 2.1 release, I&#8217;ve branched master into 2.1_branch. Development can continue in the master branch.</p>

<p>This release brings a lot of new goodies:</p>

<p>New and changed features:</p>

<ol>
<li>Redesign of the completed todos: a new overview page. Also all context and project pages have a link to their completed actions</li>
<li>New locales (es by Ignacio Ihuerta, fr by Antonin Blanc, cz by Pavel Zupa) and updated locales (de, nl)</li>
<li>You can star an action right from the form for adding a new action</li>
<li>Redesign of preferences page</li>
<li>You can now mark an action complete from the tickler</li>
<li>Project names can now contain comma (&#8216;,&#8217;) in it name</li>
<li>Context view now shows hidden and pending actions</li>
<li>Mobile improvements (we now require some javascript support on the mobile)</li>
<li>Two extra defer periods in the context menu of an action
10.There is a review page where you can see stalled or neglected projects. There is a reviewed button on the project edit page.
11.You need to change your password: migrated to better BCrypt hash algoritm for storing passwords</li>
</ol>


<p>New features (technical)</p>

<ol>
<li>There are two example ruby scripts in /doc to use the REST API to add a todo or a project template with todos from the command line</li>
<li>The tag page can now select actions from mulitple tags using AND and OR. There is no gui for this. Syntax is /todos/tag/tagA,tagB?and=tagC to select all todos with (tagA or tagB) AND tagC</li>
</ol>


<p>Under the hood:</p>

<ol>
<li>Upgraded rails to 2.3.12, jquery to 1.7.1 and jquery-ui to 1.8.17</li>
<li>Fixed several issues with the REST API</li>
<li>Upgraded the act_as_statemachine plugin. This change requires a migration. See note above!</li>
<li>Migated to bundler for gem dependencies</li>
<li>Migrated to cucumber and capybara for integration testing</li>
<li>Development mode shows a work-in-progress banner on top of the screen</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Handing Over the Keys]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.getontracks.org/news/comments/handing-over-the-keys/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-04T16:54:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.getontracks.org/news/comments/handing-over-the-keys</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you have been following posts on the mailing list and on this site, you&#8217;ll know that I&#8217;ve been in the process of handing the Tracks project on for others in the community to take over. That day has come much closer now because I have finally finished the process of adapting the old site to be published on GitHub (using the excellent <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a>). It has taken a bit of time to get right, and there may be a few glitches here and there while the DNS propagates, but things should be working. Most of the site is how it was, except that the forum is now read only, as an archive of useful information. Some of the links in the forum may be broken (for example the search facility and member profiles) in the process of generating a static version, but the basic information should still be available.</p>

<p>In due course I&#8217;ll transfer the domain name to someone else in the Tracks community, transfer the balance of the Pledgie donations, and I&#8217;ll have handed all the keys over.</p>

<p>I&#8217;d like to take this opportunity for thanking all the Tracks users for their support over the years. Tracks is in great hands, and I&#8217;m sure it will continue from strength to strength in the future.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The wiki has moved]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.getontracks.org/news/comments/the-wiki-has-moved/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-16T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.getontracks.org/news/comments/the-wiki-has-moved</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As you may know, we are in the process of moving the project and all the related web resources over to GitHub. As a first step, I have set up the <a href="https://github.com/TracksApp">Tracks project</a> as a GitHub Organisation, which makes it easier for people to administer and collaborate on the project. I have also moved the content of the entire wiki over to a GitHub wiki, <a href="https://github.com/TracksApp/tracks/wiki">here</a>. I&#8217;ve removed the old wiki to avoid confusion, and redirected the <span class="caps">URL</span> to the new wiki.</p>
<p>You can still contribute to the new wiki: if you have a GitHub account, you can edit and add pages. I hope you like the new wiki &#8211; I think it is a big improvement, and a lot more flexible.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tracks 2.0 is out now!]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.getontracks.org/news/comments/tracks-2.0-is-out-now/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-04T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.getontracks.org/news/comments/tracks-2.0-is-out-now</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tracks 2.0 is out now, and is a big release with a lot of great new features. Check out the full release notes <a href="http://www.getontracks.org/downloads/comments/tracks-20">here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tracks 2.0]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.getontracks.org/downloads/comments/tracks-20/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-13T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.getontracks.org/downloads/comments/tracks-20</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Version: 2.0</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/TracksApp/tracks/zipball/v2.0">Git <span class="caps">URL</span></a></p>
<p>A message from Reinier Balt, who has worked incredibly hard on this release. Congratulations to him and to all the other contributors!</p>
<p>Hi all,</p>
<p>After way too long time (1.7 was released on 28 feb 2009!) we are finally releasing Tracks 2.0. I&#8217;m hoping to shorten the release cycle in the future&#8230;</p>
<p>You can download this new stable version of Tracks <a href="https://github.com/TracksApp/tracks/zipball/v2.0">here</a>.</p>
<p>Important for upgrade is that the requirements for running Tracks have changed (ruby 1.8.7 / rubgems ~1.5.0). Also be aware when upgrading from a recent development version or RC version to delete the caches stylesheets and javascripts from your install. The updated installation manual can be found on github and on the Tracks website, also containing the details of the changed requirements and deleting the cached files from your previous install.</p>
<p>Please note that xuinkrbin has started a <a href="http://www.getontracks.org/wiki/Users-Manual">user manual</a> on the wiki. Anyone like to help out and write some stuff about setting up and using Tracks? A user manual if often asked for.</p>
<p>A lot of effort went into Tracks 2.0 and we have seen quite a few new (and old :-) ) contributors helping out with patches and github pull requests. Thanks to you all!</p>
<p>Now, onto the details of this release.</p>
<p>New features:</p>
<p>1. Redesign of menus and introduction of a context menu per todo<br />
2. You can now set the default tags for a project which are added automatically to a new action in that project if no tags are supplied<br />
3. Tracks now includes support of dependencies. Making an action dependent on another action will hide it until the dependency is completed<br />
4. you can now drag an action from one context to another<br />
5. Support for entering multiple actions in one form<br />
6. You can now promote an action to a project<br />
7. It is easier to view notes on the mobile interface and other interface fixes<br />
8. The project description supports markup<br />
9. support for Mail.app (message://) and OneNote (onenote://) links in notes<br />
10.The email receiver is now able to receive email from several email adresses.  In site.yml this could be set to the previous behavior (receive from one address per user)<br />
11.You can enable open signup (like in tracks.tra.in) <br />
12.Cleanup of context page<br />
13.Support for <span class="caps">CAS</span> for login<br />
14.Support for adding Tracks as a GMail Widget with instructions on the Integrations page<br />
15.Tracks now support internationalization. First translations are German and Dutch. See http://www.getontracks.org/wiki/Translating-Tracks it you like to help translating Tracks to other languages. Please report any errors in translations to our bug tracker at Assembla!</p>
<p>Under the hood</p>
<p>1. All js is migrated to jQuery and most ui-widgets are migrated to jQuery-UI<br />
2. Cucumber is added for integration testing. The RSpec stories are migrated to cucumber, so are most selenium scripts<br />
3. Upgraded to rails 2.3.11 and upgraded most gems/plugins<br />
3. Bugfixes (lots of them)</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tracks 1.7.3]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.getontracks.org/downloads/comments/tracks-173/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.getontracks.org/downloads/comments/tracks-173</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Version: 1.7.3</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/TracksApp/tracks/zipball/v1.7.3">Git <span class="caps">URL</span></a></p>
<p>An <span class="caps">XSS</span> vulnerability has been reported and is present in 1.7.2, which is also present in the development 2.0 branches (2.0RC2 and 2.0devel).</p>
<p>A new release of 1.7.3 is available from the file link. Users of 1.7x are strongly advised to upgrade to 1.7.3. If you are running 2.0RC2 or 2.0devel for production, please upgrade to the latest 2.0 tree on GitHub.</p>
<p>The manual has also been updated with upgrade instructions.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tracks 2.0 RC2]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.getontracks.org/news/comments/tracks-20-release-candidate-2/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.getontracks.org/news/comments/tracks-20-release-candidate-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Those of you who do not regularly read the forum may be unaware that Tracks 2.0 Release Candidate 2 has now been prepared by Reinier Balt. You can read all the <a href="http://www.getontracks.org/forums/viewthread/839/">details</a> on the forum, or just head straight over to Github to download the 2.0RC2 branch <a href="https://github.com/bsag/tracks/zipball/v2.0RC2">here</a>.</p>
<p>We need your help in testing it out, so please give it a try and let us know of any bugs or problems on <a href="http://www.getontracks.org/forums/viewthread/839/">this forum thread</a>. Many thanks!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Security update for users of 1.7.x and 2.0 branch of Tracks]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.getontracks.org/news/comments/security-update-for-users-of-17x-and-20-branch-of-tracks/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.getontracks.org/news/comments/security-update-for-users-of-17x-and-20-branch-of-tracks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An important message from Reinier Balt:</p>
<p>I was informed by private email that a <span class="caps">XSS</span> vulnerability is present in 1.7.2. It turned out to also exist in the upcoming 2.0.</p>
<p>A new release of 1.7.3 is made available <a href="https://github.com/bsag/tracks/zipball/v1.7.3">here</a>. Users of 1.7x are strongly advised to upgrade to 1.7.3. If you are running 2.0RC2 or 2.0devel for production, please upgrade to the latest 2.0 tree found <a href="https://github.com/bsag/tracks/zipball/master">here</a></p>
<p>I have also updated the manual with upgrade instructions.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tracks 1.7.2]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.getontracks.org/downloads/comments/tracks-1.7.2/"/>
    <updated>2010-09-26T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.getontracks.org/downloads/comments/tracks-1.7.2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Version: 1.7.2</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/TracksApp/tracks/tree/v1.7.2">Git <span class="caps">URL</span></a></p>
<p>I&#8217;m pleased to announce that Tracks 1.7.2 has been released. This is a bug fix release. This will hopefully be the last release for 1.7. We are working towards the release of Tracks 2.0 which will include new functionality.</p>
<p>You can download this new stable version of Tracks directly from Github and a manual can be found also on Github as well as on the Tracks website.</p>
<p>Fixes in this release</p>
<ul>
	<li>you can now set dates after 31-12-2010 with the date picker</li>
	<li>better warning that if you delete a context, all (repeating) todos in it are deleted too</li>
</ul>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tracks 1.7.1]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.getontracks.org/downloads/comments/tracks-1.7.1/"/>
    <updated>2010-04-13T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.getontracks.org/downloads/comments/tracks-1.7.1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Version: 1.7.1</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/TracksApp/tracks/tree/1.7.1">Git <span class="caps">URL</span></a></p>
<p>A message from Reinier Balt:</p>
<p>I&#8217;m pleased to announce that Tracks 1.7.1 has been released. This is a bug fix release. This will be the last release for 1.7. We are working towards the release of Tracks 2.0 which will include new functionality.</p>
<p>You can download this new stable version of Tracks <a href="http://github.com/bsag/tracks/zipball/1.7.1">directly from Github</a> and a manual can be found <a href="http://github.com/bsag/tracks_manual">also on Github</a> as well as on the <a href="http://getontracks.org/doc/index.html">Tracks</a> website.</p>
<p>What is new in 1.7.1:</p>
<ul>
<li>You can now add a new todo from the calendar view</li>
<li>User names can now contain dots (.)</li>
<li>Support for OneNote urls (hyperlinks to Microsoft OneNote elements)</li>
</ul>
<p>Under the hood:</p>
<ul>
<li>Several fixes for timezone support</li>
<li>Export to xml works again</li>
<li>Tracks works on current rubygems</li>
<li>Notes are styled better</li>
</ul>
<p>And lots of other fixes&#8230;</p>
<p>This release of 1.7 includes contributions made by several contributors (JPenny,Henrik Bohre, ecognito, Steven Aerts and Eric Allen of course; I hope I didn&#8217;t forget anyone.) and of course all the people who helped reporting issues on Assembla. Thank you all for helping Tracks getting better every release.</p> ]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New affiliate links]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.getontracks.org/news/comments/new-affiliate-links/"/>
    <updated>2009-08-30T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.getontracks.org/news/comments/new-affiliate-links</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You might have noticed that I have changed the affiliate box at the top left of these pages, as well as adding some affiliate links elsewhere. The Joyent affiliate programme appears to have ended, and when an opportunity came up to join the <a href="http://www.shareasale.com/r.cfm?u=188858&amp;b=179734&amp;m=22742&amp;afftrack=&amp;urllink=www%2Ejumpbox%2Ecom">JumpBox</a> affiliate program, I jumped (no pun intended) at the chance. I&#8217;ve also updated the links to JumpBox elsewhere on the site and on the manual, so if you are thinking of signing up for a JumpBox plan, please use the affiliate links and you will be helping to support the Tracks development programme.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jumpbox for Tracks]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.getontracks.org/news/comments/jumpbox-for-tracks/"/>
    <updated>2009-04-02T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.getontracks.org/news/comments/jumpbox-for-tracks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The nice people at <a href="http://www.jumpbox.com/">JumpBox</a> have just released a <a href="http://jumpbox.com/app/tracks">JumpBox for Tracks 1.7</a>. JumpBoxes are pre-built, pre-configured virtual applications which run in a range of <a href="http://www.jumpbox.com/supported-virtualization-software">Virtualization software applications</a>. You just download the JumpBox (free), then open the file with your Virtualization software. Once the JumpBox has booted, it will give you a <span class="caps">URL</span> which you can visit in a browser. The software will then guide you through setting up an account. If you&#8217;d like to try out the JumpBox without installing it, you can use the &#8220;Trial This JumpBox&#8221; button on the web site, which will let you play around with it to test it out. It&#8217;s great to have another method of using Tracks for those of you who don&#8217;t want to go to the trouble of installing Tracks and its dependencies on your computer, or installing Tracks on a web host. Try it out! You can download it directly <a href="http://download.jumpbox.com/download/tracks">here</a>. I&#8217;ll add links and instructions to the manual in due course.</p>
<p>[edited 17 Dec 2010 to update URLs]</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tracks 1.7]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.getontracks.org/downloads/comments/tracks-1.7/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.getontracks.org/downloads/comments/tracks-1.7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Version: 1.7</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/TracksApp/tracks/tree/1.7_branch">Git <span class="caps">URL</span></a></p>
<p>I&#8217;m pleased to announce that Tracks 1.7 has been released.</p>
<p>You can download this new stable version of Tracks at <a href="http://bsag.bingodisk.com/public/files/tracks-current.zip">here</a> and an updated manual can be found on <a href="http://github.com/bsag/tracks_manual/tree/master">github</a> and on the <a href="http://getontracks.org/doc/index.html">Tracks website</a></p>
<p>What is new in 1.7:</p>
<ul>
	<li>The included Rails version is updated to 2.2.2</li>
	<li>Tracks now supports recurring/repeating todos</li>
	<li>Cleanup of feed page and add feed for starred actions</li>
	<li>New interface to import an email / sms messages into Tracks (needs an email server on the same server as Tracks)</li>
	<li>New buttons to quickly defer an action 1 or 7 days</li>
	<li>Calendar view to review upcoming due actions, includes iCal feed to use in your calendar app (tested with Google Calendar, Evolution, Outlook 2007)</li>
	<li>You can now sort projects on number of active todos</li>
	<li>Support for OpenSearch. This means you can add a Tracks as a search provider in your webbrowser (tested on FF3 and IE7)</li>
	<li>We now allow users again to stay logged in on two devices at the same time</li>
	<li>Move site specific configuration out of environment.rb into site.yml for easier updating</li>
	<li>Bugfixes, including fixing OpenID</li>
</ul>
<p>(for those using 1.7RC1/1.7RC2 we dropped the initial importer of yaml files because of its experimental state)</p>
<p>There are changes to the database in Tracks 1.7, and changes to the way you configure Tracks, so please migrate your database and redo your Tracks configuration.</p>
<p>In Tracks 1.7 the site specific configuration is moved from environment.rb into the new site.yml. This makes updating environment.rb much easier without you needing to set your site specific settings after each update. After you install/upgrade to Tracks 1.7 there will be no environment.rb.tmpl anymore. You will find an environment.rb which you can leave untouched. Just fill in your settings from your old environment.rb in the new site.yml. If you have made any other customizations to environment.rb in the past, you can put them in your own configuration file (for example, in my-config.rb) in config/initializers. Please let us know if you think they should be in site.yml.tmpl.</p>
<p><span class="caps">WARNING</span>: if you update to 1.7 using git, your environment.rb will be overwritten. SO <span class="caps">PLEASE</span> <span class="caps">MAKE</span> <span class="caps">BACKUPS</span></p>
<p>This release of 1.7 will include enhancements made by a lot new contributers (Jakub, Hans, Piotr, MHarris, Piglop, Farzy, Vitaliel, McVeat and Simon; I hope I didn&#8217;t forget anyone&#8230;). Thank you all for helping Tracks getting better every release. As ever particular thanks to Luke (for updating Tracks to 2.2.2) and to Eric Allen for lots of work on a many fronts, including the site.yml improvements!</p>
<p>Very many thanks to Reinier for his hard work yet again in getting this release together!</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tracks 1.7RC2]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.getontracks.org/downloads/comments/tracks-1.7rc2/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.getontracks.org/downloads/comments/tracks-1.7rc2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Version: 1.7RC2</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/TracksApp/tracks/tree/1.7_branch">Git <span class="caps">URL</span></a></p>
<p>Reinier Balt has already announced the release of Tracks 1.7RC2, but I&#8217;ve finally (and belatedly!) found time to upload the zipped file and update the manual.</p>
<p>Reinier&#8217;s release notes:</p>
<p>We have many improvements based on the feedback on RC1. We felt we should first do a RC2 to make sure all improvements did not introduce new regressions. Please help out to test this second pre-release to find any bugs before we release 1.7 in a few weeks</p>
<p>What was new in RC1:</p>
<ul>
	<li>The included Rails version is updated to 2.2.2</li>
	<li>Tracks now supports recurring/repeating todos</li>
	<li>Cleanup of feed page and add feed for starred actions</li>
	<li>Initial importer of yaml files (still very <span class="caps">EXPERIMENTAL</span>; please send feedback on whether to include this; make backups while testing it)</li>
	<li>New interface to import an email / sms messages into Tracks (needs an email server on the same server as Tracks)</li>
	<li>New buttons to quickly defer an action 1 or 7 days</li>
	<li>Calendar view to review upcoming due actions, includes iCal feed to use in your calendar app (tested with Google Calendar, Evolution, Outlook 2007)</li>
	<li>You can now sort projects on number of active todos</li>
	<li>Support for OpenSearch. This means you can add a Tracks as a search provider in your webbrowser (tested on FF3 and IE7)</li>
	<li>Bugfixes, including fixing OpenID</li>
</ul>
<p>New in RC2:</p>
<ul>
	<li>We now allow users again to stay logged in on two devices at the same time</li>
	<li>Move site specific configuration out of environment.rb into site.yml for easier updating</li>
	<li>Bugfixes, including the upgrade of has_many_polymorphs which will fix the problem of not being able to migrate from 1.6 because of non-existing recurring_todos table.</li>
</ul>
<p>There are changes to the database (even between RC1 and RC2), and changes to the way you configure Tracks, so please migrate your database and redo your Tracks configuration.</p>
<p>In Tracks 1.7RC2 the site specific configuration is moved from environment.rb into the new site.yml. This makes updating environment.rb much easier without you needing to set your site specific settings after each update. After you install/upgrade Tracks 1.7RC2 there will be no environment.rb.tmpl anymore. You will find an environment.rb which you can leave untouched. Just fill in your settings from your old environment.rb in the new site.yml. If you have made any other customizations to environment.rb in the past, you can put them in your own configuration file (for example, in my-config.rb) in config/initializers. Please let us know it you think they should be in site.yml.tmpl.</p>
<p><strong><span class="caps">WARNING</span>: if you update to RC2 using git, your environment.rb will be overwritten. SO <span class="caps">PLEASE</span> <span class="caps">MAKE</span> <span class="caps">BACKUPS</span></strong></p>
<p>This release of 1.7 will include enhancements made by a lot new contributers (Jakub, Hans, Piotr, MHarris, Piglop, Farzy, Vitaliel, McVeat and Simon; I hope I didn&#8217;t forget anyone&#8230;). Thank you all for helping Tracks getting better every release. As ever particular thanks to Luke (for updating Tracks to 2.2.2) and to Eric Allen for lots of work on a many fronts, including the site.yml improvements!</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making yourself comfortable with git in the terminal]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.getontracks.org/articles/comments/making-yourself-comfortable-with-git-in-the-terminal/"/>
    <updated>2009-01-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.getontracks.org/articles/comments/making-yourself-comfortable-with-git-in-the-terminal</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you&#8217;re cloning or forking Tracks from <a href="http://github.com/bsag/tracks/">GitHub</a>, you might be interested in some changes you can make to your .bashrc to make using git a bit more comfortable. Henrik over at The Pug Automatic posted <a href="http://henrik.nyh.se/2008/12/git-dirty-prompt">this tip</a> for putting both your current branch name on the command line, and also indicating whether you have any uncommitted changes in the branch. If your branch has uncommitted changes, it prints an asterisk after the branch name. This is incredibly helpful for seeing at a glance what state you are in, without having to issue the commands &#8216;git branch&#8217; or &#8216;git status&#8217;. If you flit about between branches a lot, having the branch name at the command prompt can save you from a great deal of trouble.</p>
<p>You can grab Henrik&#8217;s code <a href="http://gist.github.com/31631">here</a>, or use mine below. I just foraged around among the forks and the comments on <a href="http://www.simplisticcomplexity.com/2008/03/13/show-your-git-branch-name-in-your-prompt/">this related post</a> to get a version combining the best bits of them all, then I substituted in my existing command prompt. Enjoy!</p>
<script src="http://gist.github.com/47541.js"></script>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tracks gets its own domain name]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.getontracks.org/news/comments/tracks-gets-its-own-domain-name/"/>
    <updated>2008-12-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.getontracks.org/news/comments/tracks-gets-its-own-domain-name</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&#8230;and a new home! I have now completed the migration to the new Shared Accelerator at <a href="http://joyent.com/">Joyent.com</a>, and in the process, gave Tracks its own domain name: getontracks.org. You may find that the new server feels a bit more snappy than the old one, and it should be more stable and reliable. The migration process was fairly complex, and it&#8217;s possible that some links may be broken, so do please email me if you find anything amiss. I&#8217;ve redirected the old domain to the new one, so feed readers should pick up the redirection. If they do not, you might want to enter the new feed <span class="caps">URL</span> manually for the <a href="http://www.getontracks.org/tracks/rss_2.0/">RSS2 feed</a> or <a href="http://www.getontracks.org/tracks/atom/">Atom feed</a>.</p>
<p>I was hoping to replace our Trac bug tracker with a custom solution run with ExpressionEngine (which runs this site), but importing existing tickets proved too much for my pre-Christmas brain! Instead, I imported all the old tickets into an <a href="http://www.assembla.com/spaces/tracks-tickets/tickets">Assembla space</a>. Assembla offers a number of rather cool features, and will be easier for me to administer. You can find out how to use the site to submit tickets <a href="http://getontracks.org/development/">here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tracks 1.7RC]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.getontracks.org/downloads/comments/tracks-1.7rc/"/>
    <updated>2008-12-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.getontracks.org/downloads/comments/tracks-1.7rc</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Version: Tracks 1.7RC</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/TracksApp/tracks/tree/1.7_branch">Git <span class="caps">URL</span></a></p>
<p>I&#8217;m pleased to announce that Tracks 1.7RC has been released. This is a pre-release of version 1.7. Please help out to test this pre-release to find any bugs before we release 1.7 in a few weeks</p>
<p>What&#8217;s new:</p>
<ul>
	<li>The included Rails version is updated to 2.2.2</li>
	<li>Tracks now supports recurring/repeating todos</li>
	<li>Cleanup of feed page and add feed for starred actions</li>
	<li>Initial importer of yaml files (still very <span class="caps">EXPERIMENTAL</span>; please send<br />
feedback on whether to include this; make backups while testing it)</li>
	<li>New interface to import an email / sms messages into Tracks (needs an<br />
email server on the same server as Tracks)</li>
	<li>New buttons to quickly defer an action 1 or 7 days</li>
	<li>Calendar view to review upcoming due actions, includes iCal feed to<br />
use in your calendar app (tested with Google Calendar, Evolution, Outlook<br />
2007)</li>
	<li>You can now sort projects on number of active todos</li>
	<li>Support for OpenSearch. This means you can add a Tracks as a search<br />
provider in your webbrowser (tested on FF3 and IE7)</li>
	<li>Bugfixes, including fixing OpenID</li>
</ul>
<p>There are changes to the database, and a few changes to config/environment.rb.tmpl, so please migrate your database and copy the template file and merge your personalisations with it. More upgrade instructions are in the manual in the /doc directory.</p>
<p>This release of 1.7 will include enhancements made by a lot new contributers (Jakub, Hans, Piotr, MHarris and Simon). Thank you all for helping Tracks getting better every release. As ever particular thanks to Luke (for updating Tracks to 2.2.2) and to Reinier for masses of work on a lot of fronts, not least in making it extremely easy for me to announce and distribute this release!</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Absent for August]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.getontracks.org/news/comments/absent-for-august/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-02T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.getontracks.org/news/comments/absent-for-august</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m off to Brazil for a work course again on Monday, and I&#8217;ll be away for 3 weeks. I won&#8217;t have email or web access during that time, so can I ask that you direct any questions to the forum or mailing list where other Tracks users will be able to help you. If you want to make a pull request on GitHub, or if you&#8217;ve got a patch, <a href="https://github.com/lukemelia">lukemelia</a>, <a href="https://github.com/lrbalt">lrbalt</a> and <a href="https://github.com/epall">epall</a> all have commit rights to the main repository, so you can send your request to them.</p>
<p>Have a great summer everyone, and I&#8217;ll post again when I get back!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pledgie button]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.getontracks.org/news/comments/pledgie-button/"/>
    <updated>2008-06-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.getontracks.org/news/comments/pledgie-button</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>GitHub provides a handy shortcut for creating a <a href="http://pledgie.org/">Pledgie</a> campaign, and shows the button on the repository page. We were previously accepting donations using a Paypal button, which meant I then had to do some mental arithmetic and manually update the MacBook-O-Meter to show the additional donations. Pledgie is much easier to use, so I&#8217;ve now embedded the Pledgie button on the <a href="http://www.rousette.org.uk/projects/tracks/contribute">Contribute</a> page, and also in the sidebar of the site. Click the button if you feel like making a donation! Pledgie donations can be anonymous or you can display your name proudly in the donors list, and you can use PayPal or a credit card for payment.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[BitNami screencasts in Spanish]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.getontracks.org/news/comments/bitnami-screencasts-in-spanish/"/>
    <updated>2008-06-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.getontracks.org/news/comments/bitnami-screencasts-in-spanish</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Spanish-speaking Tracks users will be interested to know that <a href="http://www.bitnami.org/">BitNami</a> have a couple of <a href="http://www.bitnami.org/article/tracks-aprende-a-manejar-tus-tareas">screencasts</a> in Spanish, showing the installation process with BitNami (which was produced by <a href="http://www.screencasts.es/">Javier Mart&#237;nez</a>) and an introduction to using Tracks. Many thanks to Antonio Santos at BitNami for pointing me to the screencasts, and for telling me that Tracks was the third most downloaded Stack on BitNami last month!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
